Hello friends, welcome once again to Honey All World channel,
friends,
in this video we are going to talk about these
data points, do not invest without seeing these 10 data points, which are those
data
points which a retail investor must definitely
see, before investing in any company,
I had recently done a run in
which I had reviewed all the Nifty-50 companies,
I had given my
impression of some data points to them, but for the last
few days I am not receiving any company,
so at that time if you definitely have to invest in some company,
my companies are not matching
with those companies which you want to remove,
then I am going to tell you such 10 data points
which you can analyze yourself
and you will not need anyone else's relations,
I always say that
be self-dependent in terms of energy,
in which company to invest or
not, so as the title of the video is that do
not invest without seeing these 10 data points,
in the video
we will give you information about
saving your investment  Let's look at some of the points
I've mentioned on the Saffron screen itself,
such as: past returns,
quarterly numbers, and performance.
Let's explore these 10 data points in the video.
Friends, I'm sharing these 10 data
points with you, and I'm going to
elaborate on them with examples:
past turn-on performance over the past two to three
years, long-term, short-term, and
medium-term. How has
Stark's dividend yield been? What is the
company's dividend yield?
What is its moving average? What is
its shareholding pattern? How is the company
's daily volume? Has the stock reached a
52-week high and 52-week low? And which
industry does the company represent?
So, let me explain these 10 points
with examples, and which
website should you visit to check these 10 points.
You can sit down with a pen and paper and
write the company's name next to these 10 points.  Keep
writing yes no yes no and deftly
create confusion yourself whether you want to invest or
not, otherwise you will not fall for the media.
Next time
before investing, let me take you an example.
Friends, if we talk about an example, I am going to
show you the example of HDFC. So,
our first point was how to check the short
term, medium term and long term returns
of a company. So, friends,
for that you do not have to do anything, you have to
directly go to Google. In Google, you have to
type "For example, I am
going to check HDFC Bank." If you type "
SDFC Bank" then
a pan will be displayed in front of you in
which one day, 5 days, one month, six months,
one year, 5 years, in this way, if I go to
five years, then I will
see the 5-year chart of HDFC. And the
best thing is that if I use the "Before Court
Cup Time" and I press it
only, then I have to press it here,
see, 141 percent is visible, so
in 5 years, before court crisis
We are seeing returns up to 141 percent
in HDFC, so we gave ₹500 return from here.
Now this would be long-term
prospective, one year, means short term
prospective, so in one year I
saw negative five percent returns and
if I take a short term prospective,
this is one month, six months, you should also
invest in this for short term, so
if we look at it in one month, then in one month
we are seeing approximately 100% returns here, so
you go to Google and type it directly,
you will get the stock, set the tenure and
calculate the percentage, so this is how we can
check what kind of returns a company is giving us
in short term, medium term and long term.
Now
if we want to check the trend of the company's results for the last three years, then
how can it be checked,
friends, there is this website, its name is
business-standard.com, see, I am
showing you the quiz, business-standard.com,
you will type Business Standard on your internet browser,
its side will open,
here in the search bar you have to write the name of the company  If I
type HDFC Bank in the pin,
HDFC Bank will open on
this website. Then if I go to the company,
I will see HDFC Bank here. As
soon as I like and share it,
I will get a drop down option
or financial group. You can
check doctor predictions in the news of every category.
Here, when you go to finance,
because I want to check the results, and by
going to friends, I will get to know what
kind of results HDFC Bank has given for 3 years.
But if I
want to check the quarterly numbers, then I will go directly to the quarter from here.
Going to the quarter, I will see that for example, you had given the numbers of March 19,
why for the Jain community, so we can
see some of my numbers here,
how their net profit has
decreased compared to the previous quarter. So this is a very good
way
that we can see how the
company's shares have trended in the last 3 years. Love Yagya,
we have a quarterly review.
Now the third point is that you are drinking,
never invest without seeing what happens, now you are drinking,
friends, BJP fibers
also  We can introduce business-standard.com
and if you want, we can also refer to it.
When we search on Google, we
see the search behind it written here.
We can also refer from here.
Finding the search is not a big deal. Just by looking at the
name of the company, whatever comes up
behind it will come up in front of you
on Google itself. This time, this is the right of 19.
Friends, what happens by searching is that the price
of the share divides the meaning of the company. In
the market,
how much an investor
is willing to invest for every rupee that the company earns. This is the price. The
more the pressure, the more expensive the
stock is considered. But the more expensive the stock is,
it also represents this thing.
The more the
value is available on that topic. Now, for example, at
what time are
they seeing the semen of HDFC Bank here, let's take it as a basis. The
average speed between 12 and 20, it is
not very expensive right now. If we
ask HDFC Bank, there are some banks
behind which we see around fifty-sixty,
those are expensive interests there.  But there is a lot of
chatting going on because at this time no
one is focusing much on the banks.
I myself had written in my videos that they are in the
business of lending money. If we look at them, then the
PDS system of banks seems to be
falling. If you
look at the background, it is a good thing that you are
drinking a lot, that is, you are
drinking for 510 rupees, that means there is a
company to invest more in.
Now you see, if you are drinking a good company with good income, that
means 10 to 15 to 20 rupees, 22%
turmeric, it is considered that you can invest in it, then you
must also review this data.
Now the fourth point is whether the
company tweets or not. It shows
that if you invest in a company
for the long term, then the
return of the chart which you will get is that the
stock value is increasing. Even if the company
gives different returns, that too is not your return. There is an
account somewhere for that too. Business Standard is
a very good website, we
get many things from here. Business Standard will be
informed as soon as I get HDFC's
truth that in the summary  If I go, I also
find that this HDFC
also seems to be giving us different business. Look, I did
one on the last date, if in 2019, then
it keeps updating all the data. Business
Standard. Sometimes it happens that the data gets
updated after a day or two, but it keeps getting updated.
It is on the website of Vitamin. I consider this
website to be enough
and from here I go and extract the company's data.
Yes, there are many other
websites from where we can get data
on different companies. That means
I will also get more information and a secondary source
of earnings after investing in this Gypsy.
Now after this, let's see
what is the fifth point which must be
looked at. RSS RSS. What is the
relative strength
in the index, which is the index of HDFC Bank,
how much
strength is there in the chart. Now I will show you the effect for that. There is a
website, see friends, take
note of this, tradingvoot.com. Now when you
open it, you
can check the chart of any company online. Now this
is the chart of HDFC in front of us.
Now look, this is causing mental
harassment.  Due to this, its
size is seen around fifty-seven,
see, its size is
seen around 157, when
I should explain it to you in very simple language, when
RSI starts going around 70-80, that is, it starts
going into the overboard zone, from there the
selling becomes normal, when RS itself starts going over
hundred and that is, it
slips below 10, although below 15-20,
people start considering it as bad,
but a very good company, if
not cheap, at least Arya Satya, and if it is found, then
from here,
buying can come again in it, so
this is a point for short term investors also,
and see this, people invest,
long term investors do it, at what
time should they enter the stock, which is
not at the right pitch, if it is coming
at 70-80 and there is inquiry thousand, they will invest,
hence the stock will come, perhaps if it starts getting nine and a half, then
entry ISI can be seen at the right level,
now another point movie  Also,
check between the Avengers movies to see if the trend of the
90-day, three-
month period is consistent with the line
you're seeing last night. This 90s
moving average, meaning the stock momentum from the number group,
is declining. This means we could
see a soft declining trend in the coming days as well. The
stock price could go down, which long-
term investors look at. The
moving averages tend to press the indicator on the day they start showing upwards.
People enter at that time. The
short-term moving average is also
looked at for investors. This is used by short-term investors.
You
can find all this information on tradingguru.com. Make a
note of it in your notes.
Now, if we talk about the next point, the next
point is shareholding patterns. Friends, the
best reliable source for this
is NSCindia.com. Here,
you can go to the search bar and find SDC. To see this
type of shareholding
pattern, I'll
go to company information and I'll see shareholding
patterns here.  From this, I will know
how many shares the promoter has and
how many the public has. It is
important to see that at this time the data is being uploaded that 70% of the shares are held by the public in HDFC Bank and since 2016 the promoter has held this. Why is it important to see this?
Because if the promoter has sold all his
holdings and the entire stock is
with the public, then the public panics more. As soon as the
promoter writes a few
next news, we see selling immediately.
If the promoter has
more shares, then a maturity is visible.
Even with slightly bad results, the stock does
not fall immediately. So, all these things, an
investor should definitely look at the data.
After that, how much are the Delhi volumes?
We can also get this data on addasiindia.com
or as soon as you search here, you will
see the quantity credit in the security belt delivery position.
Look at the delivery, you can know
what is the quality in it,
how many people are coming to Delhi on this,
how much internet is there because you see here the
delivery percentage is also being shown.
The more the delivery, that means that
more people are taking one-sided positions.
Apart from this, whatever percentage is left is
only of intraday readers, so the
more internet rivers there are on any topic, the more
time stocks are there.
Retail investors have to keep these things in mind.
After that, the fees have been paid and the people, that is,
how much maximum and western it has shown in the last 52 weeks,
this also
gives a slight idea about where the stock is standing.
Now, for example, the bank which after showing a height of 1300 feet,
is standing at 947 at this time
and the low was 3878, so somewhere it is
standing just a little ahead of the middle, so
that psychologically the calculation starts forming in your mind,
after looking at your data format, you should only look at the price and then
enter. Media says, you should
not do exam center, 1 liter part has been done. The
most important thing for the industry is
which industry your company belongs to, the company
in which you are going to invest, that company
represents this industry
because but when we talk about the list of banks now, the
bank is in a landing business, now
in the landing business, it means that there will be a
transaction of money here.  And at this time
we know that the credit profile of people
is not very stable,
so the industry which
Faridabad represents is an agriculture sector
company or a pharma sector company,
these days this chapter makes more sense,
so all these data points are based on this thing
that which industry, so
every one has an idea that which
industry will see more growth in the coming time,
so bank shot is
not a good investment destination for some time, for 2 years,
you should definitely consider this industry,
ask yourself in your mind whether
this industry will start in the next one or two years, do the
micro factors
allow this thing at this time, so friends,
in this video we talked about
not investing without looking at these 10 data points, I hope
you understood these 10 points, if
not then definitely comment in the comment box on
this and we will elaborate on it, hmm,
come to the comment box and reply and I
hope after this whatever investment you make will be
more mature, so friends, with this note,
advisor  Video Thank you so much for
watching hai kar
do